Knots have a long and varied history throughout time, and today I'm going to show you how to make one of the great ones.
My name is Robert Segundo, and I'm going to teach you how to make a clove hitch.
Now a hitch, technically, isn't a knot, but it falls in the same category of kind of the macrame style.
So what we're going to do is, we're going to look down to our table here, and we can see I have my rod, here, that I'm going to attach my line to.
What I'm going to do is, I'm going to take my line initially, I'm going to roll it up and over, and then bring it under, like so.
Then it's going to go over the standing end that was there, and I'm going to take my working end back up and over.
And it's going to come under, and then back through the loop, like so.
There you go.
This is basically two half-hitches put together, and this is just a clove hitch.
And it's really tight.
I mean, you can hold things with it.
You can't put a whole lot of tension on it,because it will slip through.
But it's good enough if you're just trying to hold some items down.
Let's do that one more time.
Let's pull this up...and out, like so.
Once again, we'll go over, we'll go under, over our standing end.
And we'll go over like so, back under, and through the loop we've created, and there it is.
There's our clove hitch.
My name is Robert Segundo, and enjoy tying knots.